Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
Powerful energy readings...
Directly overhead!
Splendid, Commander Shultz...
Now, we'll be able to hold our heads high before General Goer.
If that man hears this, he'll report to
Lord Dessler, as if he'd done it himself.
However... This is our victory.
Planet Gamilas
Capital City Baleras
Lord Dessler's Palace
Ilun Phezeron.
A message from Shultz for our lord. He wishes to give a report to you.
Shultz?
You gave him command of the Plat base, in the galactic hinterlands' Zol system.
Oh, yes... I left a brigade of second-class Gamilans
in charge of the planet Teron's conquest, didn't I?
I am Valke Shultz, commander of the armies besieging Teron, my lord.
Shultz, you are contacting us without your commanding officer, Goer's approval.
Normally, this act would be grounds for—
Now, now. Let him speak, Hiss.
Y-Yes, sir.
Your report, Shultz?
Y-Yes, sir!
This morning, at Tam 10:06 Gamilas Standard Time, after fierce combat,
the Plat advance base destroyed the
Teron FTL-capable spaceship Yamato.
What of it?
Well... I wanted to report our victory to you directly.
You requested my presence merely to report something so obvious?
I wished to provide some small additional glory
for the Great Gamilas Empire's founding celebration...
I shall remember your loyalty.
That's enough! Be off, Shultz.
Garle Dessler! Hail to our leader!
Celestra, is it true that a Teron ship crossed the light-speed barrier?
This is the first I've heard of it.
And you, Vice-Commander?
N-No, neither have I.
I would imagine not.
Commander, what did Lord Dessler say?
He said he would remember our loyalty.
Foolish Terons.
Had they simply surrendered,
they could have lived on, as we have.
SID, overlay Alpha Squad's zone of operations.
Executing command.
I've linked geographic data with the heat sources projected to be the Gamilas base.
Balance control, are those vents closed?
Boatswain!
Keep at it!
Who the heck wants to drown in a spaceship? Not me!
How are those extractor pumps?
We're closing this area! Hurry!
Okay, we have it stopped here.
This wound's nothing. Just put some spit on it, and it'll heal.
Hey, Makoto!
Harada is seeing patients elsewhere.
Are you okay?
Stay strong! I'll patch you up right now!
First-aid complete here.
Okay, come here.
Right!
You'll be okay.
But how did the enemy attack us?
We don't know how!
Team 3 to deck 4 damage control.
Finished the check. No problems.
Good to hear it.
Hey, Yama, how long will we have to sit at the bottom of the ocean?
We still aren't out of the solar system. Will we really make it to Iscandar?
I will never allow another of my ships to sink.
Since the moment I left Earth,
my life's been in old man Okita's hands.
We'll do what we can. That's all.
Is that true?
Yes. A beam weapon that uses satellites.
The large amount of debris made me curious.
So I had the intelligence officer scan it.
It isn't debris. These are all enemy satellites.
I believe they've been using the satellites as beam weapon relays. In other words...
They can target the entirety of Pluto.
Then, if we surface, they'll just hit us again!
Can we find the timing they use to attack?
I'll try.
I hope that explosive camouflage fooled them.
It's only a matter of time.
But for now, we wait and believe in Kodai and the other pilots.
And when the time is right, the Yamato will strike back.
Hey, Nemoto...
That Yamamoto rookie's a real babe, isn't she?
EM restrictions in effect. Communication not sent.
I know that, Navi-baby.
Command not recognized.
Loosen up a little, would you?
3,000 kilometers until target reached.
EM restrictions lifted. Sugiyama, follow me!
Roger!
Sugiyama!
Bravo 3 is lost.
Guess we chose a winner.
Teron fighters? Where?
Above the 137th Unmanned Environmental Modification Plant.
The Environmental Plant?
The AA System is engaging them.
It appears there are several others hiding as well.
Probably survivors from the Yamato. Launch the interceptors!
Yes, sir.
Beautiful...
This is Bravo 1. EM restrictions lifted. I've found the Gamilas base!
Let's go, Yamamoto.
Wait!
What is it?
Two o'clock.
Two o'clock?
Message from Bravo 1, Kato.
He has engaged target object 5.
So that's their base?
Coordinates confirmed.
But we aren't sure it's the enemy base.
Even if it's uncertain, you can't win some wars without placing a bet.
Weapons Officer, load missiles. Prepare to launch.
Preparing to launch missiles.
Engine Officer...
Engine on line. We can reach max speed whenever you like.
Boatswain, how are the Wave Motion Shields?
We've done what we can. Inertial control is also on line.
Now we can fight with our feet on the ground.
Attention, all crew. This is the captain.
We now move to undersea operations, to counterattack the Gamilans.
All crew to combat station 3.
Get the engine running!
Yes, sir!
Spin the trim. Blow the main tank.
Raise bow thirty-five degrees.
Raise the Yamato!
The enemy came from within the auroras. Meaning...
Warning! Warning!
Sensors are indicating an unreadable energy emission.
What?
That's...
Lieutenant Kodai!
This is it. This is definitely the enemy base!
Signal on radar. Enemy fighters above base.
Impossible! What happened to the concealment field?!
It's functioning properly.
C-Commander...
Remain calm, Ganz. Ship-borne planes are nothing to fear.
Go!
Direct hit on concealment system. Field dissipating.
Concealment field lost.
Something surfacing at location where the Yamato sank.
What?!
What is that submarine?
You can't tell? That's the Yamato!
What should we do? We've already given our report to Lord Dessler.
Damn you, Yamato...
Prepare to fire Reflecting Satellite Cannon!
Preparing to fire Reflecting Satellite Cannon.
Select relay satellites.
Selecting relay satellites...
6, 33, 28, 57...
It's irrelevant. We'll simply sink it again.
Our report was merely a bit early... Nothing more.
We will now begin our attack.
Bravo 1, withdraw from the area.
It's not that easy!
Bravo 1, come in!
This is Alpha 1, Kodai. Requesting backup from the Yamato.
Alpha 1 has discovered the camouflaged enemy base.
Using the equipment on board, it will prove difficult to destroy.
So that's the real base?
Well done, Kodai.
Captain...
Can you see anything that resembles a beam launcher?
No, nothing like that.
It's probably hidden below the surface or in the sea.
Yes, that is the biggest threat to the ship.
Kodai, Yamamoto are to stay in the area, to confirm location.
Confirm it? But how?
See with your eyes.
My eyes?
Yes... Your eyes!
Darn it! This wasn't the right base?
Stop complaining.
The cavalry's here.
Shinohara! Nemoto!
And that's not all...
Go get 'em!
They look like a bunch of thugs.
Go!
Roger!
Deploying reflectors 6, 33.
There it is.
I have the satellite signals.
Analyzer!
Beginning analysis.
Now deploying 28, 57.
Relay satellites identified.
Target locked. AA interceptor missiles ready for launch.
Fire AA interceptor missiles.
Last time, you survived. But you won't survive this.
Energy charge complete.
Fire Reflecting Satellite Cannon!
Done.
Alpha 2, Yamamoto, to Yamato.
I've identified the enemy cannon. Location is a frozen bay.
Roger. Transmit data now.
Roger.
Prepare to fire. We'll destroy the enemy cannon.
57 is lost. It's been shot down from the surface.
So, the Yamato noticed the satellite cannon.
Prepare cannon to fire again!
This time, we'll change angles,
firing from outside their effective range.
Level the ship!
Inertial control working properly.
Space gyros reversed. Dropping starboard ballast!
Level!
Ship leveled. All inspections reported no problems.
Type-3 rounds set with timed fuses.
Target is the enemy beam cannon.
Load main gun with Type-3 rounds!
Ranging complete.
Fire.
Countdown to impact.
10.
9.
8.
Charge complete!
7.
6.
5.
4.
Fire the Reflecting Satellite Cannon!
This is Alpha 1. Destruction of enemy beam cannon confirmed.
We did it.
We will now move to destroy the enemy base.
Raise bow twenty degrees. Launch the Yamato!
No signal from the Reflecting Satellite Cannon.
This can't be happening...
Yamato approaching rapidly!
Commander, it's too dangerous here. Please evacuate!
Evacuate?
As long as you survive, you have
the chance to restore our honor!
Ranging complete. Targeting complete.
Air-to-surface missiles ready to fire.
Open fire!
Four enemy ships are leaving the base.
We will pursue. Switch main guns to shock cannon mode!
We will protect you. Please, be safe...
Prepare to switch to Geschtam Navigation! Hurry!
Enemy is charging toward us!
I won't let you get them!
The Destoria has fallen.
Geschtam Jump!
Enemy has warped away.
The Gamilas advance base on Pluto is finished.
No more planet bombs will fall to Earth.
This is Kodai.
Returning to the Yamato.
Plat has fallen?
Hiss, was I dreaming? Did the Teron ship not sink?
Yes, sir. I was given the same information.
Shultz abandoned his base, to retreat from the front lines, correct?
Y-Yes.
"Retreat" is not a word in the Gamilas dictionary.
Victory... If not victory, death.
Yes, sir.
Terons, huh?
The Yamato has left Pluto's orbit.
We did it, Kodai.
Yeah, we did.
We did it, Brother.
We will return to our original course. Set engines to combat speed 1.
Course adjusted. Engines at combat speed 1.
Episode 6
The Sun Sets on Pluto
The unknown calls to us
Does your courage burn to go there?
We rush on a journey
For everyone to survive together
For happiness
Though there is pain
And sadness
We will not be defeated
Those who know the beautiful Earth
Restore its wonders
Bring it back, bring it back
The road to tomorrow
Not afraid anymore
Determined to reach our destination
With different emotions in each of their hearts,
the crew of the Yamato now leave the solar system behind.
Before them lies a galaxy no human has ever seen.
Say a prayer for those who set sail,
and a goodbye to those left behind.
Let your feelings be heard.
Farewell, Earth.
We will return!
Next time: Farewell to the Solar System.
There are 355 days left before humanity is extinct.